how's it going everyone this is Nick at
bobbin.com and today we're talking about
the best fat burning supplements for
women right off the bat I gotta make it
clear calories are the most important
thing when it comes to burning fat you
want to consume fewer calories than you
burn that leads to weight loss while
calories are the most important thing
when you are losing weight there is some
interesting signs suggesting that fat
burning supplements could potentially
help a lending hand so today we're going
to be talking about a wide variety of
different fat burners we've got the best
non-stem fat burner because a lot of
them contain caffeine we've got to have
the best for appetite suppression the
best for thermogenesis and more so stick
around we're going to make you an expert
in fat than this and you're gonna decide
which one here is the right product for
you before I go on I should make it
clear that this is not medical advice
and I am not a medical doctor that's
disclaimer that's important on basically
any kind of supplement content but
especially ones like this uh if you're
going to make any changes to your
supplement regimen or your nutrition
regimen or your exercise regimen or
anything like that make certainly speak
to your own doctor so you can get
professional advice and make sure that
the plan that you landed on it is going
to be squared away with you the
medications you're on you're in personal
history and your individual preferences
[Music]
the most common question that we get
asked about fat burners I want to just
tell you what the top pick on our list
is because you know what I respect your
time your place it to be it is cage
muscles clean burn these are fat burning
pills and they got a really interesting
breadth of ingredients that address the
question of fat loss from various angles
so it's a pretty killer product I'm
gonna get all the way into it in just a
second but first
what's a fat burner like what what are
these ingredients that we keep talking
about fat burning supplements I
recognize it is maybe a bit of a
misnorma because it is not like you take
a pill and then just the fat starts
melting off of your body right calories
the most important thing here but some
of the ingredients in these products can
potentially help with you burn more
calories at rest so there are three main
ways these kind of products work devices
thermogenesis which again that is when
you can burn more calories at rest than
you would have otherwise if you hadn't
taken the product very very common in
these sorts of supplements and
interesting research has suggested that
it helps to slightly increase the
temperature in your body not in a way
that you'll really notice it but that's
what thermogenesis means like it
increases the heat like it creates the
heat thermogenesis in the body so that's
one way that it can help you to burn
more calories the second one is fat
oxidation which that actually is like
fat burning right and there are some
evidence that a lot of ingredients out
there are for example egcg a type of
antioxidant found in green tea it coaxes
the body into burning more fat for fuel
than it would have otherwise the last
one is appetite suppression which may be
the most important category here because
you can take something that'll make you
burn a couple hundred more calories but
if you eat a couple hundred more
calories that's all going to be for not
right these ingredients basically
through completely different mechanisms
uh can cause you to be less hungry to
Crave less and thereby you're not going
to struggle so much with the lower
calorie right so those are the three
ways fat burning supplements work and
now I'm going to talk about our favorite
fat burning supplements on the market
for women starting with our absolute
favorite which again is clean burn so a
lot of the ingredients I just mentioned
are in this product right we have the
capsaicin or this one's called capsimax
which is a patented form of cap station
that has some studies leaking into
increased fat oxidation increase
thermogenesis and lower appetite same
goes to the green tea extract here which
is 80 catatins 50 egcg which is the one
you really want to look for on these
sorts of products if you want to have
the green tea extract specifically for
weight loss purposes there's also El
carnitine El tartrate and then finally
there's gymnema Sylvester very unusual
that is a plant extract that could
potentially help you to taste sugary
Foods less like it seems like dull The
receptors of something in the mouth but
we've had some studies on moderately
obese individuals and that found they
lost five to six percent of their body
weight when they were taking this
particular supplement simply because
they crave sweet dirty food less so
that's interesting so that has like an
element of appetite suppression in
addition to these other ingredients that
have elements of fat oxidation
thermogenesis as well so pretty
interesting supplement we also named
this our best all-natural fat burner
because there's nothing artificial in
this right you're talking plant extracts
a lot of people when they hear fat
burning supplements they get wired
you're taking some weird Franken Foods
designed in a weird lab what this is is
uh it's natural products right it's
green tea extract it's a red chili
pepper extract and so on there's also no
artificial flavors in this no artificial
sweeteners even the capsules that this
comes in are vegan friendly so if you
are a vegan vegetarian Halal kosher or
just don't like the idea of having your
pills wrapped in bone uh that's not the
case here so you are able to have this
if you're being a vegetarian lastly it's
third party tested for Purity and
potency uh so that means basically that
you can be confident that even though
you're getting a fat burning supplement
which is a bit intimidating to some
people you can be rest assured that it
doesn't have any weird other ingredients
that have made their way into the
capsules it's just what's right here on
the label next up you want to get ready
for this one because Wolverine's Femme
or therm if I had a normal accent is our
favorite belly fat burning fat burner in
addition to being the best of the money
it's actually remarkably inexpensive
because in this little pill bottle you
are going to get 90 servings and the
cost winds up being around 35 cents per
serving so 35 cents per day because it's
just one pill per serving so it's a
really impressive price what they've
come up with here we end up we needed
the best for the money also the best
belly fat now to be clear spot reduction
in fat which is occurring which is like
saying I'm going to lose some fat from
my elbow I'm gonna loosen fat for my
belly that's not really how how the
metabolism works but that said there are
interesting ingredients in here that
aren't just linked to burning more
calories but also some more Direct
effects on fatty tissue so for example
there's coleus for Scully in this which
might increase lipolysis which is the
breakdown of fats we've also got some
banaba Leaf which might decrease the
production of fat cells and there's
Garcinia Cambogia as well which has
links to reducing fat mass now again
total calories cuddle micronutrients
your exercise regimen your sleeve very
very important but still like with this
many different ingredients with this
many different ways of potentially
reducing belly fat what we've found is
that like if if that's your main goal
here
so long as you're also following the
other advice for losing fat this could
provide some extra relief in that regard
simply because there are so many
ingredients in it that are helping to
reduce fat in so many different ways we
also considered them the best research
backed fat burner for the sheer number
of ingredients here you can find a study
supporting each and every one for use in
a weight loss plan so there's cayenne
pepper of course just mentioned has
links to Fat oxidation and reduced
appetite but also thermogenesis there's
also caffeine in here which has the
links to fat loss thermogenesis and
reduced hepatitis as well what's
interesting as well is that the caffeine
actually comes from guarana so for one
you're getting 100 milligrams of
caffeine which for a fat burner is
pretty low like your average 12 ounce
cold brew from a coffee shop is 150 160
milligrams of caffeine so it's not going
to be an overwhelming amount of caffeine
and the fact that it comes from guarana
is interesting because some evidence
suggests that that is it provides like a
more pleasant less jittery form of
simulation so for many folks when
they're taking caffeine for
thermogenesis they find it more helpful
to get it from that form and that's what
uh theorem has used here from Sovereign
so that wraps up our dissertation on
Wolverine's thumb it is our best fat
burner for belly fat the best research
back fat burner the best for
thermogenics and also shockingly the
best for the money as well it's just 35
cents a day before we move on to our
next pick I did want to say that uh this
is kind of a lot of information and a
lot of ingredients so my point being if
you want to get a written version of
this video uh we wrote one so you can
just go to Google and do bar band best
fat burners for women and the article
for this video will come up so that way
you can go through the information at
your own pace look at the studies that
we've been citing and so on and make up
your in mind as to which of these
products is right for you for now though
we're going to talk about the fastest
working fat burner hourglass is our pick
for the fastest working fat burner the
reason for that is that uh it has a lot
of glucomannan in it right we really
like it for appetite suppression there's
some really interesting data out there
showing that uh folks who take it like
they lose weight over time because
they're eating less the reasons for that
is that this is a very certain kind of
fiber that swells up in the stomach once
it hits the stomach it swells a little
bit so it makes it something feel like
it's Fuller than it is and thereby it
manages to reduce appetite so the
fastest working fat burner are hourglass
fit here it's all pale just vegetarian
friendly though and on top of that you
have some extra nutrition here there's
some B vitamins some zinc and some
chromium as well five hdp is also a very
interesting ingredient for appetite
management so combine that 5-HTP with
the glucomannan the Japanese conjunct
tree and you have like a pretty
interesting product for appetite
suppression here the next product is a
question we get asked a lot which is the
best fat burner for women over 40. uh
it's no surprise as we get older our
metabolism changes a little bit and our
resting metabolic rate tends to decrease
so they tend to be different needs or at
least like differently emphasized needs
for Forks Over 40. transparent Labs was
our favorite for this one the reason why
we like this one honestly uh it has a
solid emphasis in appetite suppression
as well as well as like fat oxidation
too the idea here being that uh it
actually becomes necessary to eat fewer
calories is as you get older than it was
when you were younger so this has a bit
of an emphasis on appetite including a
good dose of 5htp which as I just
mentioned more satiety and also more
satisfaction in general helps people
sleep and so on so it has like some
interesting uh beneficial effects
outside of just like what you're eating
you've also got theanine here which also
helps the mental state there's some
caffeine too this isn't non-stem but
it's just 120 milligrams of caffeine and
then you get some theanine with that as
well and many people find that caffeine
and theanine combined put together helps
to create more of a sort of a relaxed
approach to caffeine that just like
increases your focus would that make me
really jittery or wired right while also
having a thermogenic effect on your body
so you have the appetite suppression of
5hcp and green tea but you've also got
some extra fat oxidation and
thermogenesis from other ingredients
including caffeine cayenne pepper and
also cinnafarin which is an interesting
extract That You Don't See very often
that's some pretty curious that he's
supporting it so that's transparent Labs
uh we are a fan of this bad boy yeah
buddy
the lights over 40. we're a fan of it it
does have uh some stimulating
ingredients but they do have a non-stem
version available as well if that's what
you would prefer in any case they have a
nice emphasis on both uh helping people
to burn a bit more calories at rest
helping people to manage their appetite
as well and also just generally making
one a little bit more satisfied with the
process because of that extra serotonin
that it may help you produce now one
audience that is very attentive in the
world of fat burners is uh bodybuilders
and female bodybuilders so a question we
often get asked is the best like fat
burning stack that's when you're taking
multiple products at once on top of one
another to have ideally synergistic
effects or at least stacking effects you
can enjoy the benefits of all of them so
in the female bodybuilding Community
this supplement stack has become pretty
popular we have to agree this is like a
really good one the company is huge
supplements and they've got both a
lemonade and exterminate eliminate might
sound like a diuretic it is not it's
about eliminating body fat and so it's
exterminate the idea is you put them
together and you get all the benefits so
the reason these are sold as separate
products really is because one has
stimulants and one does none right but
there are also some ingredients in the
two that could work synergistically so
we've got hesperidin and lemonade and
naring gin and sinephrine and
exterminate and there's just some
interesting evidence that like taking
these sorts of extracts together can
help to enhance their properties not
just have them both at the same time but
they could work synergistically a little
bit so if you're convinced by the
science behind the thermogenic effects
of these ingredients the amount of
calories they can burn really is
superior to everything else here
particularly when the two of them are
combined together so that can be a
special useful for female bodybuilders
or for anybody Builders because
especially as one approaches the date of
the competition you're low in calories
you're high on cardio and there's a good
chance that you simply can't consume
fewer calories than you're at four
competitors for physique competitors and
for bodybuilders that can make all the
difference so a lot of people find that
combining thermogenic aspects like this
can really help in that Journey now when
it comes to the best pre-workout fat
burner the best fat burning pre-workout
uh we're going back to transferring Labs
here as we've mentioned really great
company really transparent a little bit
dosing it's the kind of thing where if
you don't believe anything I'm saying
that's fine you can go to the website
they'll tell you themselves and they'll
show you the proof for it uh on PubMed
with scientific references so it's
really a good company at a yeah
instilling confidence in their consumer
base this is their pre-workout called
lean
um the chance of formulation a couple
times over the years but generally this
is the Pre-Workout for folks who want
some extra fat burning ingredients in it
so one is actually not crazy high in
caffeine for a pre-workout which we find
is always ideal or typically ideal for
our female viewers because they tend to
weigh less than men right so here we've
got 220 milligrams of caffeine which is
certainly not nothing but it is again
it's about what you'll find in the 16
ounce cold brew or so like roughly
speaking and then it's also got
citrulline beta alanine and betin
anhydrous which are very popular
pre-workout ingredients that can help
with blood flow endurance and power
output as well so very very good
pre-workout there uh it's not crazy high
in caffeine and also you've got some
ingredients in there for increased fat
loss next up we've been talking a lot
here today about different stimulants in
pre-workouts uh caffeine is the main one
but also sometimes there's like your him
being and stuff like that non-stem fat
burners they are I think most of them
have stimulants but Legions Phoenix
right here is a stem free product uh
Legion is another company it's a little
bit like transparent Labs but they're
very good at being transparent and
citing their sources and all that kind
of stuff so this stem free fat burner
from Legion is a bit more creative with
this ingredient profile black ginger
extract which has some interesting
anti-obesity effects in some literature
and it's also grains of paradise here
and I've spent some interesting research
with grains of paradise this fan if you
were to extract like the bioflavonoids
in there it couldn't activate your brown
fatty tissue and also it can help to
increase your uh your calorie burn for
the day so it has like a thermogenic
effect as well again I encourage you to
click on the link in the description
below if you're interested in checking
out this product and learning more about
them because Legion does hopefully tell
you what every single one of the
ingredients does and also all that
information is on the article version of
this video that you can Google the last
fat burner I want to talk about in this
video is the pinkest one as well it's
lean Bean which we named the best fat
burner for appetite suppression it's
interesting looking at the products that
are great for thermogenesis or the ones
that are have a lot of fat oxidation
ones personally I think this is a really
good one to end on because appetite
suppression is a really important part
of the weight loss puzzle or rather
calorie restriction is an appetite
suppression can help you to get there
despite that word suppression this is
not too scary a topic because it uses
all natural ingredients the one we're
talking about here again is glucomannan
which the same ingredient that was an
hourglass fit it's got roughly the same
amount of glucomannan that you take per
day this isn't just a glucobanon
supplement though there are also a few
other ones here including chlorogenic
acid for some research suggests can
reduce your absorption of calories as
well so that combination of appetite
suppression and also potentially reduce
calorie absorption can be really
effective combination for a fat burn
like lean beans this is definitely our
favorite fat burner for appetite
suppression plus it's vegetarian friend
also just because we've been answering
so many common questions about these
we've done like how do fat burners work
what are the ingredients in fat burners
when to take a fat burner is another one
I want to quickly address just because
it's such a wide variety of ingredients
in this it's typically half an hour
before each meal but the main thing is
with fat burners is generally speaking
if we're going to have a really like
blanket answer to that question you take
them about a half hour before a meal
because that's going to help to kick in
the appetite suppressive effects and
help to kick any other effects that it
might have for instance for example the
decreased calorie absorption that some
of these ingredients may help to confer
you take it like about a half hour
before a meal that's going to help a
kick in in time for the meal to actually
hit your stomach read the ingredients
have a look at the research talk to the
brand and above all talk to your doctor
alright that does it for our video on
the best fat burners for women there are
large large variety of products out
there with a whole lot of different
ingredients there uh and as I mentioned
they're active in various areas of
different ways they could potentially
help to expedite weight loss so there's
a lot to take in I do encourage you to
Google the full article or just go Bob
and best fat burners for women I'm glad
you hung on this long it's nice to see
you thanks for watching and we'll see
you for the next video
foreign